# 這個魚好像跳出來啦
It seems that the fish has jumped out.
# 擋在這裡
It gets stuck here.
# 它還活的
It's still alive.
# 把它給煮啦
Let me cook it.
# 你看
Look!
# 這個魚還活的哦
The fish is still alive, isn't it?
# 一晚上啊 在那裡
It has been staying there for the whole night,
# 還沒跑
and didn't run away.
# 它又不跑
It just didn't run away.
# 它有吃的
It got food there.
# 這個甚麼 吃的草
What is it? It has eaten grass.
# 把這個打一下花
Let me slice it a few times.
# 這樣就 更入味
Then the flavour, can be better absorbed.
# 搞定
Done!
# 搞點生薑
Some ginger,
# 搞點生薑給它
let me give it some ginger.
# 這個生薑
This is ginger.
# 加點料酒
Put some cooking wine.
# 加點鹽
Put some salt.
# 鹽要搞多一點
I need a bit more salt.
# 搞點它這裡
Put the salt here on the fish.
# 搞點醬油
Put some soy sauce.
# 它還活的
It's still alive.
# 再加點油
And some oil too.
# 再給它摸一摸
Then, give it a massage.
# 好啦 腌個半個小時 我們再來處理它
Alright! Marinate it for half an hour, then we can go to the next step.
# 鍋燒熱 再把油放下去
Let's heat the wok and then pour the oil.
# 這個薑也放下去
Let's put in the ginger as well.
# 還要煎
It needs to be fried for a bit longer.
# 你看 這個肉全裂開啦
Look! The meat has already cracked open.
# 丟點辣椒一下
I throw in some chilli.
# 沒辣椒不好吃
It won't taste good without chilli.
# 可以啦 起鍋
Alright! It's done!
# 它這個薑 辣椒不要
The ginger and the chilli are no longer needed,
# 全部都不要
neither of them.
# 就要這個魚
I want only the fish.
# 這個魚
The fish...
# 好殘忍 你看
So cruel, look!
# 剛剛還活潑 活潑亂跳的
It was still jumping, jumping around energetically a few moments ago.
# 現在就變成這樣子的
But now, everything has been changed.
# 沒事
No worries.
# 反正煮的很好吃
Cuz it must be very tasty.
# 很靚吧
Beautiful, isn't it?
# 哎呀 好香
Aya! It smells so good!
# 嗯
Um!
# 很香這個魚
The fish smells really nice!
# 被火燒啦
It's burnt.
# 加點青菜
Put some veggies.
# 給它蓋一下被子
Let me give it a blanket,
# 蓋一下它的傷口
to cover up its wound.
# 做好啦
Done!
# 先嘗一下它的尾巴
I try its tail first.
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 嗯 可以喲
Um! It's not bad!
# 好香啊
It smells so good!
# 這個魚是小的 很嫩的
This is a small fish. It's so tender.
# 嗯
Um!
# 真的很好吃哦
It's really tasty!
# 好像我比較喜歡吃香的 (註︰這個「香」，應該是指「香口」，英語裡似乎沒有一個很合用的字)
It seems that I prefer deep fried food.
# 這個 有點上火 (註︰為免外國人不清楚「上火」這概念，這裡情境應該可以避一下)
It's ah, not really that healthy,
# 有一點辣
and a bit spicy too.
# 微辣 不是很辣
It's not too spicy, just a bit.
# 嗯 吃點魚翅
Um! Let me get a fin.
# 魚翅都可以直接咬碎
The fins are also crispy.
# 還很不的
It's really not bad.
# 這個魚我都養了錯
I've been keeping the fish for,
# 養了差不多半年啦 才養那麼大
for half a year, before it gets to this size.
# 不好容易把它養大 它又跳出來
I put so much effort in raising it. But it jumped out.
# 這不能怪我哦
It's not my fault.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 留著晚上來
It will be a dish,
# 下飯
of my dinner.